Guide to the Frank Durkan Papers AIA.008
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series III: Northern Ireland Peace Process, 1984-2006, 1982-2006
  - IRA Ceasefire: "Northern Ireland: Conflicts of Sovereignty", 1992 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - IRA Ceasefire: Official Statement Folder, Oct 1993-Sep 1994 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - IRA Ceasefire: Correspondence, 1994-1998 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - IRA Ceasefire: Consulate General Ireland of Ireland Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - IRA Ceasefire: The Writing Campaign - Political Prisoners List, May 1995 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - IRA Ceasefire: Publications by Irish and Irish-American Organizations, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - IRA Ceasefire: Press Clippings, Aug 1994-Sep 1994 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - IRA Ceasefire: Press Clippings, Sep 1994-Oct 1994 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - IRA Ceasefire: Press Clippings, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - New Ireland Forum Report, May 1984 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - "No Border, No Cry?: The Peace Process and the Causes of Conflict in Northern Ireland" by Tom Hayden, Feb 1998 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - O'Dwyer, Paul: Correspondence John McMichael, Ulster Defence Association (UDA) re: UNorthern Irleand Sitatuion, Anglo-Irish Agreement, Dec 1986 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Orange Parades: Communication, press statements, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Orange Parades: Irish Parade Emergency Committee, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Orange Parades: Press (Quinn brothers death stories included), 1998 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Orange Parades: Press,correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Orange Parades: Publication: Chapter and exerpt from book: 200 Years at the Organge Citadel: A Nationalist Perspective" by Michael Farrell, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Orange Parades: Publication: "For God and Ulster: An Alternative Guide to the Loyal Orders" Pat Finucane Center., 1997 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Orange Parades: Report: "Eyewitness: Conflict in Northern Ireland." Irish Parades Emergency Committee and Brehon Law Society, New York., 2001 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Orange Parades: Report: "Law and Lawlessness: Orange Parades in Northern Ireland." Irish Parades Emergency Committee and Brehon Law Society. New York, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Orange Parades: Report: "Marching and Disorder Conflict in Northern Ireland: 2003 International Observers' Report." Irish Parades Emergency Committee and Brehon Law Society. New York (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Orange Parades: Report: "One Day in August." Pat Finucane Centre. Derry., Aug 1995 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Orange Parades: Report: A Report Upon the Conduct of the Royal Ulster Constabulary: Case Histories Upon the Violation of the International Covnenant on Civil and Political Rights by the RUC During the Marching Seasons of 1995, 1996, 1997." Lawyers Alliance for Justice in Ireland, Inc. Denville, NJ., circa 1997 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Orange Parades: Report: "Sectarianism on Parade: Orange Parades in Northern Ireland. Summer 2005 International Observers' Report." Irish Parades Emergency Committee and Brehon Law Society. New York. (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Policing: Irish American Unity Conference Report "Study on Policing in Northern Ireland", Sep 1999 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Policing: McPhilemy, Sean / Prentice v. McPhilemy et al (author of The Committee), 1998 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Policing: The Nemesis File by Paul Bruce - exerpt, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Policing: Patton Commission - public submission`, Jan 1999 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Policing: Royal Ulster Constabulary (RUC): Patton Commission/Policing Debate, Aug 1999-Dec 1999 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Policing: Royal Ulster Constabulary (RUC): Patton Commission/Policing Debate, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Policing: Royal Ulster Constabulary (RUC): Research for Hearings - Articles, 1982-1999 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Policing: Royal Ulster Constabulary (RUC): Research for Hearings - Freemasons, 1984, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Policing: Transcript and evidence about RUC, Feb 1999 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Policing: "War and Peace: the Role of Police Lessons of Los Angeles Police Reform for Northern Irleand" submitted to the Northern Ireland Policing Commission by Tom Hayden, Feb 1999 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Republican Sinn Fein: Ó Bradaigh, Ruarí - Visa Denial and Repeal Committee, 1994-1996 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Republican Sinn Fein: O'Bradaigh Visa Denial - Albert Reynolds comments on WBAI radio interview, 1995 (Box 26, Cassette 6)
  - Republican Sinn Fein: Presidential Addresses to Ard-Fheis, 1994, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Republican Sinn Fein: Statements and Publications, 1993-1998 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Sinn Fein: Gerry Adams visit to United States, Feb 1994 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Sinn Fein: Information Packet, Nov 1995 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Sinn Fein: Press Clippings, 1996-1998 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Sinn Fein: Statements and Publications, 1995-2000 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Series IV: Legal Cases, 1975-2003
  This series which is the largest of the collection documents the work of Frank Durkan as lawyer and advocate for civil and human rights. The series includes files on cases Durkan worked on as well as cases of personal interest to Durkan, such as those included in Subseries F, G, and H on Human Rights and treatment of Prisoners both in Northern Ireland and other countries.
  - Subseries A. U.S. v Irish Northern Aid Committee (INAC; NORAID), 1969-1982
    - Annual Testimonial Dinner Dance Journal, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Civil Action Suit I: Complaint, 1970-1972 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Civil Action Suit II: Subpoenas and Depositions, 1970-1972 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Civil Action Suit III: Opinion, Research Materials, 1972-1973 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Civil Action Suit IV: Correspondence, Research Material, 1972-1973 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Compliance File, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Counter Claim, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Counter Suit I, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Counter Suit II, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Counter Suit III, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Court Records, 1972, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Defendant's Memorandum of Law in Opposition to the Plaintiff's Motion to Dismiss Defendant's 3rd and 4th Counterclaims, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Discovery I, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Discovery II, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Documents from 2nd Circuit - Appendix I, 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Documents from 2nd Circuit - Appendix II, 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Foreign Agents Registration Act of 1938, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Foreign Agents Registration Act: Correspondence I (includes Fort Worth 5 correspondence), 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Foreign Agents Registration Act: Correspondence II, 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Foreign Agents Registration Act: Supplemental Documentation, 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Foreign Agents Registration Act: Supplemental Documentation I, 1973-1975 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Foreign Agents Registration Act: Supplemental Documentation II, 1973-1975 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Foreign Agents Registration Act: Supplemental Documentation III, 1973-1975 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Foreign Agents Registration Act: Supplemental Documentation I, 1976-1978 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Foreign Agents Registration Act: Supplemental Documentation II, 1976-1978 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Foreign Agents Registration Act: Documentation Request I, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Foreign Agents Registration Act: Documentation Request II, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Foreign Agents Registration Act: Resubmission of Statements under the Foreign Agents Registration Act, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Furman Air Freight Corp. v. Irish People, Sister Goulding St. Hugh, NORAID, 1974-1978 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Harrassment - Via Foreign Agents Act I, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Harrassment - Via Foreign Agents Act II (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Legal Proceedings, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Motions, Memoranda, etc. I, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Motions, Memoranda, etc. II, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Motions, Memoranda, etc., 1981 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Memorandum Opinion and Order, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Memorandum and Order, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Order to Show Cause, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Order to Show Cause for Preliminary Injunction, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Order to Show Cause: Harrassment (Foreign Agents Act), 1977 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Petition for Writ of Certiorari to the U.S. Court of Appeals, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Photographs from Caucus, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Plaintiffs Response to Defendant's First Set of Interrogatories and Document Requests, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Pleadings, 1972-1977 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Pleadings and Documentation, 1971-1978 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Pre-1979 Material (correspondence), 1976 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Summary Judgment Papers I, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Summary Judgment Papers II, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Summary Judgment Papers III, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Supplemental Statements to the U.S. Department of Justice, Bi-annual, 1974-1977 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Statement of Points and Authorities in Support of Defendants Motion for a Preliminary Injunction, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Working Files and Papers I, 1977-1980 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Working Files and Papers II, 1977-1980 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - FBI Files: 97-5299 Section 1, 1970-1972 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - FBI Files: 97-5299 Section 2, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - FBI Files: 97-5299 Section 3 I, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - FBI Files: 97-5299 Section 3 II, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - FBI Files: 97-5299 Section 4, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - FBI Files: 97-5299 Section 5, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - FBI Files: 97-5299 Section 6, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - FBI Files: 97-5299 Section 7, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - FBI Files: 97-5299 Section 8, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - FBI Files: 97-5299 Section 9, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - FBI Files: 97-5299 Section 10, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - FBI Files: 97-5299 Section 11, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - FBI Files: 97-5299 Section 12, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - FBI Files: 97-5299 Section 13, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - FBI Files: 97-5299 Section 14, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - FBI Files: 97-5299 Section 15, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - FBI Files: New York File 97-2700 Section 1 I, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - FBI Files: New York File 97-2700 Section 1 II, 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - FBI Files: New York File 97-2700 Section 2 I, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - FBI Files: New York File 97-2700 Section 2 II, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - FBI Files: New York File 97-2700 Section 3, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - FBI Files: New York File 97-2700 Section 4 I, 1974-1975 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - FBI Files: New York File 97-2700 Section 4 II, 1975-1977 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - FBI Files: New York File 105-109381 Section 1, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - FBI Files: New York File 105-109381 Sub A Section 1, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - FBI Files: New York File 105-109381 Sub A Section 2, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - FBI Files: New York File 105-109381 Section 2, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - FBI Files: New York File 105-109381 Sub A Section 3 I, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - FBI Files: New York File 105-109381 Sub A Section 3 II, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - FBI Files: New York File 105-109381 Sub A Section 4, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - FBI Files: New York See Refs (also Chicago Information), 1970-1975 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - FBI Files: Durkan, Frank- INAC NY See Refs, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - FBI Files: Durkan, Frank- INAC BUFiles, 1971-1973 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - FBI Files: Durkan, Frank- INAC NY Main File, 1973-1977 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - FBI Files: Flannery, Michael NY See Refs, 1969-1972 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - FBI Files: Flannery, Michael, BUFiles I, 1963-1973 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - FBI Files: Flannery, Michael, BUFiles II, 1963-1973 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - FBI Files: Flannery, Michael, NY Main File, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - FBI Files: Higgins, Matthew INAC BUFiles, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - FBI Files: Higgins, Matthew INAC NY See Files, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - FBI Files: McCarthy, John INAC BUFiles, 1971-1974 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - FBI Files: McCarthy, John INAC NY See Refs, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - FBI Files: McGowan, John BUFiles, 1970-1974 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - FBI Files: McGowan, John INAC NY Main File, 1973-1974 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - FBI Files: McGowan, John INAC NY See Refs, 1970-1973 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Subseries B. Attorney General of the United States v. Irish People, Incorporated, 1980
    In the 1970s, the newspaper, The Irish People, was sued by the Attorney General of the United States in an attempt to force the paper to register as a foreign agent. The U.S. Attorney General argued the paper had received monies and donation of space from the Irish Northern Aid Committee, an organization which was suspected of sending monies to fund the activities of the IRA in Northern Ireland. The paper was considered complicit in this enterprise.
    - Appeal, Correspondence, Exhibits, 1974-1983 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Announcements, 1982 (Box 33, Folder 41)
    - Appeal, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Appeal, 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Appeal: Appendix, Apr 3,1981 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Appeal: Motions, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence and Memoranda, 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - FBI Files: "States Secret", 1978 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - IRS filing (notice to register as foreign agent); Legal documents, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Memorandum and Order, 1976-1977 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Motions I, 1976-1980 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Motions II, 1976-1980 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Motions, Affidavit, 1976-1980 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Motion for a Protective Order; Electronic Surveillance Disclosure, 1976-1980 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Motions for Protective Order; Disclose and Suppress I, 1976-1980 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Motions for Protective Order; Disclose and Suppress I, 1976-1980 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Motions, Interrogatories, 1976-1980 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Motion to Dismiss, 1976-1978 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Motion to Dismiss, 1976-1980 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Motion to Dismiss, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Subseries C. U.S. v. Mackin (Desmond Mackin)
    In 1978, Desmond Mackin was charged with the attempted murder of a British Soldier in Ireland. He fled to the States and was subsequently arrested in 1980 and charged for this crime. In a landmark ruling, the Judge found that Mr. Mackin could not be extradited because his offences were political, i.e., he was a member of an uprising group (the IRA) and his alleged offense was attributed to furthering the aims of this political group and their uprising. After avoiding extradition, the INS initiated deportation proceedings and Mackin elected to be deported to the South of Ireland to avoid risking deportation to British authorities.
    - Appeal Papers I, 1978-1981 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Appeal Papers II, 1978-1981 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Appeal Papers, Aug 1981 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Appeal Decision, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Appelees Brief, 1980-1981 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Bail Affidavits, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Bail: Emergency Application for Bail ... Pending Government's Appeal, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Bail Motions, Defense Pleadings I, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Bail Motion, Defense Pleadings II, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Bail Motions, Defense Pleadings: Exhibits, 1978-1981 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Brief in Support of Petition for a Writ of Mandamus, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Circuit Court Discussions / Deportation Papers, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Courtesy Copy: Court of Appeals, 1981 (Box 33, Folder 42)
    - Draft Briefs, Pleadings I, 1981, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Draft Briefs, Pleadings II (Brehon Law Society), 1981, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Draft Motion Papers, Memorandum I, 1976-1981 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Draft Motion Papers, Memorandum II, 1976-1981 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Dual Juristic Act: Docket, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Dual Juristic Act: Post-Trial Correspondence, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Dual Juristic Act: Press Notes, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Exhibits, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Extradition Request, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Extradition Request (Hon. Buckwald), 1981 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Extradition Requests (Hons. Sand, Cooper), 1981 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Government Briefs, Memoranda, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Government Exhibits, 1970, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Memoranda re: Extradition, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Memorandum in Support of Motion to Dismiss, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Motion to Dismiss, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Motion to Dismiss: Exhibits 1-55 80 Cr Misc #1 p. 54, 1978-1980 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Notice of Motion to Dismiss Extradition Request I: Exhibits 1-8, 1973-1981 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Notice of Motion to Dismiss Extradition Request II: Exhibits 9-11, 1973-1981 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Notice of Motion to Dismiss Extradition Request III: Exhibits 12-15, 1973-1981 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Notice of Motion to Dismiss Extradition Request IV: Exhibits 16-28, 1973-1981 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Notice of Motion to Dismiss Extradition Request V: Exhibits 29-31, 1973-1981 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Notice of Motion to Dismiss Extradition Request: Petitioners Reply to Government's Memorandum, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Opinion Orders: Buckwald, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Opinion: U.S. District Court Decision - Buchwald, Naomi Reice, Aug 1981 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Orders, Opinions, Quotes, 1978-1980 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Post-Hearing Memorandum: Respondent Mackin, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Post-Trial Memoranda in Support of Requested Extradition, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - in Re: Mackin: ABC News Closeup "To Die for Ireland" transcript, Jun 12, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - in Re: Mackin: Newspaper Articles, 1973-1981 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - in Re: Mackin: Notes, Replies I (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - in Re: Mackin: Notes, Replies II, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Statutes: Lord Diplock / Court of Human Rights/Terrorism I, 1972-1981 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Statutes: Lord Diplock / Court of Human Rights/Terrorism II, 1972-1981 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Statutes: Lord Diplock / Court of Human Rights/Terrorism III, 1972-1981 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Stips, Correspondence, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Testimony: DiMaio, Dr.; Asbury (FBI), Blackbourne (Medical Examiner): Direct and Cross I, Feb 20, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Testimony: DiMaio, Dr.; Asbury (FBI), Blackbourne (Medical Examiner): Direct and Cross II (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Testimony: Argument of Counsel Point I, Mar 5, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Testimony: Garrett - Direct and Cross, Mar 30, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Testimony: Harvey - Redirect / Mackin - Cross, Apr 1, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Testimony: Mackin - Direct, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Testimony: Masterton - Direct / Perez - Direct and Cross, Apr 7, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Testimony: Masterton - Cross / Lynagh - Direct and Cross I, Apr 8, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Testimony: Masterton - Cross / Lynagh - Direct and Cross II, Apr 8, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Warrants of Arrest I, 1974-1981 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Warrants of Arrest II, 1974-1981 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Courtesy Copy: Court of Appeals, Part I, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Courtesy Copy: Court of Appeals, Part II, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Research: Decisions - Abu Eaiu, Castione, Garcia-Moa, Gonzalez, Kam-Shu, Hooker, Meunier (extradition) I, 1978-1981 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Research: Decisions - Abu Eaiu, Castione, Garcia-Moa, Gonzalez, Kam-Shu, Hooker, Meunier (extradition) II (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Research: Decisions - Abu Eaiu, Castione, Garcia-Moa, Gonzalez, Kam-Shu, Hooker, Meunier (extradition) III, 1978-1981 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Research: Decisions - Abu Eaiu, Castione, Garcia-Moa, Gonzalez, Kam-Shu, Hooker, Meunier (extradition) IV, 1978-1981 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Research I, 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Research II, 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Research III, 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Research IV, 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Other Cases (Ireland), 1979-1980 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence and News Articles I [RESTRICTED], 1981-1982 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence and News Articles II [RESTRICTED], 1981-1982 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence and Notes I (includes Telegram from Jane Fonda to Edmund Muskie) [RESTRICTED], 1980-1981 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence and Notes II [RESTRICTED], 1980-1981 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Expenses [RESTRICTED], 1981 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Statues: Lord Diplock: Report of Official Commission / Terrorism (Secret Document, Minister of Defence G. Britain) [RESTRICTED], 1978 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Subseries D. U.S. v. Harrison et al (George Harrison)
    George Harrison, along with Tom Falvey, Michael Flannery, Patrick Mullin and Danny Gormley, was arrested and tried for illegal shipment of arms to Northern Ireland. The case hinged on the fact that Harrison and his co-conspirators believed that their contact, George DeMeo, was himself an agent of the CIA and therefore the United States government was cognizant of their arms dealing and complicit in allowing this activity to continue.
    The files contain the trail transcripts along with many legal documents and newspaper clippings. Of note is the Jury Verdict slip, showing all defendents not guilty on all counts (Box 15, Folder 21).
    - Affidavit and Exhibits in Support of Defendant's Request re: Jury Selection Vol. I, 1981-1982 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Affidavit and Exhibits in Support of Defendant's Request re: Jury Selection Vol. II, 1981-1982 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Affidavit Regarding Extradition, 1982 (Box 33, Folder 43)
    - African National Congress, 1987 (Box 33, Folder 44)
    - Alcohol, Tobacco, and Firearms (ATF) Records, Dec 22, 1981 (Box 33, Folder 45)
    - Brinks, 1982-1983 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Character Statements, 1981 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - "Congress '86" (Irish Socialism), undated (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Counsel Notes, Drafts, Pre-Trial Motions, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Curragh Camp Escape, 1959 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Demeo, George: Probation Record [RESTRICTED], 1965-1982 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Department of State Office of Munitions Control, Dec 1981 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Falvey, Thomas: US Magistrate's Form, Jun 20, 1981 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Fingerprints, 1981 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Flanagan, Martin: Subpoena, 1981 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Flannery, Michael: Complaint, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) Requests, Jun 1987-Aug 1987 (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Gormley, Danny: Investigation, 1981 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Government Exhibits, 1981 (Box 34, Folder 14, Folder 12, Folder 13, Folder 11)
    - Harrison Prisoner Record [RESTRICTED], 1981 (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Harrison Statement (before Jury; manuscript), [1981], undated (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Harrison Statement (Before Jury; typescript), 1981 (Box 34, Folder 15)
    - Indictment, 1981 (Box 34, Folder 16)
    - Irish American Defense Fund, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Irish Cases: Lawyers (list), 1982 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - July Indictment, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Jury Selection, 1981 (Box 34, Folder 17)